Magnus Jan Krynski Collection CPAA 91.17
Connecticut Polish American Archives
Magnus Jan Krynski Collection
1966-1984
CPAA 91.17
Connecticut Polish American Archives
6.0 Linear feet
This collection consists of materials that belonged to Magnus Jan Krynski (MJK) of North Carolina. A successful translator, author, educator, and proponent of human rights, Krynski was active in Polish affairs and Polish American politics and culture. A native of Poland, he came to the United States in 1949 and obtained an extensive education which he applied to translate several volumes of Polish poetry into English and also become chairman of Duke University’s Department of Slavic Languages and Literature. There are a plethora of documents relating to his professional life, translating work, and political activity in this collection.
Krynski, Magnus Jan, 1922-1989
Biographical/Historical note
Magnus Jan (John) Krynski (MJK) (1922-1989) was born in Warsaw, Poland and came to the United States in 1949. He received a Bachelor of Arts from the University of Cincinnati, a Masters of Arts from Brown University, and a PhD in Polish and Russian literature from Columbia University. He was an educator at the University of Pittsburgh, Kenyon College, Ohio State University and Duke University, where he also became a chairman of the Department of Slavic Languages and Literature in 1966. He was an author of many articles about Polish 20th century literature and translator of Polish poetry. Krynski together with Robert A. Maguire were co-translators of three major collections of Polish poetry by Tadeusz Rozewicz, Wisława Szymborska and Anna Swirszczynska. Wislawa Szymborska received the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1996. Krynski was an active member of American PEN Club and the Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences. In the eighties, he became active in national and local politics. He was active in groups such as Pomost North Carolina, Freedom Foundation, International Society for Human Rights, and the Heritage Foundation. He was a Washington D.C. representative and a founder of American Polish Political Action Committee - AMPOLPAC, chairman of the North Carolina Ethnic Voters for Reagan-Bush and delegate to the Republican National Convention in 1984, and co-founder of the North Carolina Committee for Solidarity with Solidarity. He authored statements, position papers, and memoranda on East-West trade issues, human rights, and economic sanctions for US State Department of National Security Council, and the US Congress. He married Elizabeth Girardet from New Hampshire in 1952 and retired in 1987. He passed away from a heart attack in 1989 in his town of residence Durham, North Carolina.
Scope and Contents note
This collection contains of materials related to Krynski’s work as a scholar, author and educator including manuscripts, printed copies of his articles, drafts of translations, conference papers, research notes, notes from trips to Poland, outgoing/incoming correspondence with Polish writers, scholars, and editors (both in Poland and in the US). Furthermore, it includes memos, letters, and notes related to Duke University’s Slavic Department and documents of Krynski’s political activities such as correspondence, memos, fliers, position papers, news clippings, interviews, and speeches. Also included is a set of transcripts from Jozef Wittlin's Radio Free Europe literary program broadcasted between 1955 and 1966 from New York.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Mrs. Elizabeth Krynski donated the material to the Connecticut Polish American Archives in 1991, two years after Mr. Krynski's death.
Human rights -- Poland -- 20th century; Poland -- History -- 20th century; Polish Americans -- Connecticut -- Politics and government; Polish Americans -- Intellectual life; Polish Americans -- Political activity; Polish literature -- 20th century -- Translations into English; Polish poetry; Radio Free Europe
- Magnus Jan Krynski- Curriculum vitae, 1970, 1976, 1979, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Marquis Who's Who, Inc.- Biographical sketch and correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Magnus Jan Krynski obituary by Robert A. Maguire, 1990 (Bin 1, Folder 2a)
- “A survey of postwar Polish literature (1944-1959) with special reference to Soviet influences (abstract)”- Magnus Jan Krynski, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Interview with Magnus Jan Krynski by Robert Maguire in periodical “Literatura na swiecie” (Literature in the world), [n.d] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence- Waclaw Sadowski from Literatura na swiecie, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Magnus Jan Krynski application for promotion, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Maquire, Robert- Curriculum vitae, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Maquire, Robert - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Marek Hlasko: the lyrical naturalist" essay by Magnus Jan Krynski (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Inner empire: two poems from Poland by Marian Piechal" by Magnus Jan Krynski & Robert Maquire, in Slavic Review, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- “Mrozek, Tango and American campus” essay by Magnus Jan Krynski, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Yugoslavia 1970: The Country, The Slavic Seminar and Some Polonica" essay by Magnus Jan Krynski & drafts (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Warsaw Seminar for Slavists: August 20-September 18, 1972 by Magnus Jan Krynski (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Report on 17th Annual International Seminar for Slavists, Warsaw, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- “Politics and poetry: The case of Julian Tuwim” by Magnus Jan Krynski (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Tuwim: Politics and Poetry- Addena and related material, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Article about “Tuwim”- Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- “Julian Tuwim: A Story Continued” by Magnus Jan Krynski; “Orbis Scriptus”, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Piesn o biciu - by Julian Tuwim [n.d] (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "The poetry of Tadeusz Różewicz " by Magnus Jan Krynski & Robert Maquire [n.d] (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Translator's introduction to: "’The Survivor’ and other poems by Tadeusz Różewicz” by Magnus J. Krynski & Robert A. Maguire, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Reviews of “The Survivor and other poems”, 1978, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- "The Poetics of Tadeusz Rożewicz" by Magnus J. Krynski & Robert A.Maquire, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Tadeusz Rożewicz: Pogrzeb po polsku [programme]1971, 3 essays from: Teatr niekonsekwencji. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Tadeusz Rożewicz - drafts of translations, introduction, [n.d] (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Tadeusz Rożewicz - subsidiary material, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- “Anna Swirszczynska: thirty four poems on the Warsaw uprising” translated by Magnus J. Krynski & Robert A. Maquire, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Anna Swirszczynska/Robert Maquire/ Magnus J. Krynski- “I Was Building the Barricade” translation- Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Foreword and preface to "Building the Barricade", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- "Poland 1977: The Emergence of Uncensored Literature" by Magnus J. Krynski (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Princeton University Press- Szymborska and Rozewicz translations- Correspondence about editing, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- “Two poems by Wislawa Szymborska” Translated and annotated by Magnus J. Krynski and Robert A. Maquire in The Polish Review, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Wislawa Szymborska correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- “Sounds, Feelings, Thoughts: The Poetry by Wislawa Szymborska” [translated by] Magnus J. Krynski & Robert A. Maquire, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Wislawa Szymborska - drafts of translations, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Wislawa Szymborska poems: “Wielka Liczba”, 1976 (2 copies); “Poezje” (Box 1, Folder 35a)
- "Sounds, Feelings, Thoughts"- Publicity, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- “Two poems by Henryk Jasiczek” – Magnus J. Krynski translation, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Magnus J. Krynski's translations of Baranczak's poems & correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Baranczak's collection- Advertising and promotion planning, newspaper articles, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Selected poems by Ewa Lipska, translation by Magnus J. Krynski, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Magnus J. Krynski notes from trip to Poland, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Notes from the meeting with Jerzy Andrzejewski, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- First Conversation with Rozewicz, August, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Conversation with W. Wantula- Notes, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- A note on Ewa Lipska, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
- “Poland's Literary ‘Thaw’: Dialectical Phase or Genuine Freedom?” Magnus J. Krynski in The Polish Review (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Magnus J. Krynski's review of “The New Polish Poetry: A Bilingual Collection” by Milne Holton & Paul Vangelisti, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Magnus J. Krynski’s review of "The New Polish Poetry: A Bilingual Collection" by Milne Holton & Paul Vangelisti in Slavic Review, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- YIVO Institute for Jewish Research- Notes [n.d] (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Janina Czermanska- Notes, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- A reading of Polish poetry, Duke University event [1981]- Introduction, fliers, notes (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Problems of translating Polish literature- The Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences (PIASA) Annual Meeting- Paper by Magnus J. Krynski, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Translator's note by Jan Kott, from Tadeusz Borowski "This way for the Gas...";Pisarz naszego wieku" by Zygmunt Gren, from Zycie Literackie, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Notes from articles from "Odrodzenie", 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Tadeusz Borowski- Materials for publication, 1959-1971 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Borowski and American Literature- notes [n.d] (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Incoming and outgoing correspondence with Polish writers, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Correspondence with Polish writers, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Correspondence with Publishers, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Speech for Polish students, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Ludwik Krzyzanowski- Curriculum vitae, [n.d] (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Ludwik Krzyzanowski /The Polish Review – correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Ludwik Krzyzanowski /Krystyna Olszer/The Polish Review, 1973-1981 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Irene Nagurski/ The Polish Review, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Evaluation of Jerzy Krzyzanowski article for Polish Review [n.d] (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Address to the Board Members of Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences (PIASA) - MJK, [1982?] (Box 2, Folder 1)
- PIASA- Minutes, membership, reports, etc., 1968-1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- PIASA - Correspondence, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Literary section of PIASA/Frank Mocha- Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Frank Mocha's promotion correspondence, 1977; "Pushkin's Poltava...", 1975; “The Karamzin-Lelewel Controversy” by Frank Mocha, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Madeline Levine - Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- "Fragments of Life: Miron Bialoszewski Poetic Vision" by Madeline G. Levine in Slavic and East European Journal, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence- Various publishers about placement of articles, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence- Twayne Publishers about book of Rozewicz translations, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Jerzy Giedroyc/Instytut Literacki- Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Notes from trip to Poland, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Proposed research project [1978?] (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous information about literary world in Poland, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Polish writers- Biographical information, [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Chekhov's "Three sisters"- Notes, [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Late 19th century Russian dramas- Notes ("well made plays"), [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 16)
- French plays ("well made plays")- Notes, [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Polish poetry in English translation, 1968-1978 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- “Data on Aleksander Wat”[n.d] (Box 2, Folder 19)
- International Research & Exchange Board (IREX)- Grant award, correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- ZAIKS Award, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Salamon, Joanna - "Medytacje" (photocopy), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Salamon, Joanna - “Poem from Houston” and correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- "Komunikat" by Adam Zagajewski (photocopy), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- "W fabrykach udajemy smutnych rewolucjonistow" by Julian Kronhauser (photocopy), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Adam Zagajewski- Letter & poems, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Julian Kronhauser- Letter & poems, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Aleksander Janta- Index to personal archives, [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 28)
- The summer course for Slavists at the University of Warsaw, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Stanislaw Baranczak visit at Duke- Correspondence, publicity, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Correspondence- Departmental business, research, book orders, etc., June 1970-May 1971, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Duke University, Slavic Languages Department- Memos, correspondence, 1970-1986 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Duke University - Academic Council, Undergraduate Faculty Council- Minutes, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Duke University- Miscellaneous correspondence, The Chronicle, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Slavic Departments at other Universities- Correspondence, biographies of professors, programs of study, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Student evaluations of Magnus J. Krynski, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Slavic conferences, seminars lectures, etc.- Related documents, 1978-1987 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- “Polish literature in exile”, by Jerzy R. Krzyzanowski- North Eastern Slavic Conference, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- “Slovak emigre literature” by Stanislav J Kirschbaum- Paper for North Eastern Slavic Conference, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- “The traditional and the contemporary in Ukrainian emigre Literature” by Roman V. Kuchar- North Eastern Slavic Conference, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- “The traditional and contemporary in Serbian emigre literature” by Mateja Matejic- North Eastern Slavic Conference, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- North Eastern Slavic Conference- Invitation, notes, program, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies (AAASS) convention- Program, newsletter, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Study Tour to Soviet Union & Munich Center- Oklahoma University Summer, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Polish Press Photography (exhibit)- Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Miscellaneous correspondence- Subscriptions, grades, copies, etc., 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- “Anatomia terror”- Discussion with Polish writers in Odra, [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Polish Embassy- Correspondence, visa information, admissions information for colleges in Poland, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Institute of Literary Research (IBL), Warsaw-Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Book exchange - Duke University- Polish National Library, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Warsaw University, Exchange Department (Polonicum), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Academic exchange with Poland - University of Kansas- Information, correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Polish Summer Programs (in Poland)- Program, course outline, 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Kosciuszko Foundation- Fliers, magazine, [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Bibliographic citation- Books on Poland- mem-o-grams [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Book orders- Michal Krynski, Stefania Krynska- Notes (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Catalogs- Polish books and products, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Edward Federenko's publications, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- The Wedding by Stanislaw Wyspianski, translated by Floryan Sobienioski & Hesketh Pearson, Magnus J. Krynski notes, [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 59)
- “The Myth Against Fourfold Background”- Artur Sandauer[n.d] (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Articles by and about Artur Sandauer, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- "Genre and hero/Fathers and sons" Magnus Jan Krynski? [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Josip Brodsky poems, 1962-1972 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- ”Proba pamieci”; ”Proba ‘Metropolu’” by Andrzej Drawicz, [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 64)
- "Slonce wschodzace: sztuka w 2 aktach" by Maria Dolinska & letter, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Julian U. Niemcewicz letter to British Under Secretary for the Foreign Department(copy) [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Tri Quarterly - Polish issue- Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Nowe Sztuki 14-17/1983, indeks 1982 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Polish National Anthem (with English translation) [n.d] (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Recommendations, references, etc., 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Kociecki Leszek- Personal documents, biography, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Syllabi, etc. from Columbia and Brown University, 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Anna Akhmatova and acmeist poetics - Aileen Masterson & Magnus J. Krynski criticism, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Student paper on Andrei Amalrik's "Will the Soviet Union Survive Until 1984: A Summary and Comment", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Duke University & University of North Carolina faculty-Correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, notes, Solidarity memorabilia, 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Krynska Stefania- Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Michal Krynski letters, 1966-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Zygmunt Hertz- 1967-1969; April 4, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Incoming correspondence- March 1974-October 1978, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Outgoing correspondence September-December, 1967 (Also from Robert Swan) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Outgoing correspondence November-December, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Outgoing correspondence January-February, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Outgoing correspondence March-August, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Outgoing correspondence November 1969-June 1970, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Outgoing correspondence July – November, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Outgoing correspondence November 1971-August 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Outgoing correspondence August 1972-May 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Outgoing correspondence May-November, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Outgoing correspondence November 1973-August 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Outgoing correspondence September 1974 - March 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Outgoing correspondence March-September, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Outgoing correspondence September 1975 - April 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Outgoing correspondence April-October, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Outgoing correspondence October 1976-March 1977, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Outgoing correspondence March - August, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Outgoing correspondence August 1977 - February 1978, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Outgoing correspondence February - November, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Outgoing correspondence October 1978 - May 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Outgoing correspondence June 1979 - January 1980, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Outgoing correspondence January - June, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Outgoing correspondence (*several incoming) October 1980-March 1986, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- "North Carolina's lobbyist for Solidarity", Durham Morning Herald December 5, 1982 & letter (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Articles about Magnus Jan Krynski, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Interview in Gwiazda Polarna, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Magnus Jan Krynski- Speech notes, October 28, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Magnus J. Krynski 's speeches, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Speech at the University of North Carolina, March 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Washington University Speech, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- “The Solidarity movement, the martial law, the Western response", speech by Magnus J. Krynski, [n.d] (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Notes [to the article about human rights in Poland?] (Box 4, Folder 9)
- [An article or speech about Poland - by Chrystal Guy or Magnus J. Krynski?] (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Slavic Studies at University Of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign- Information packet, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- “What's wrong with the voting record of Polish-Americans in the 98th Congress?” By Magnus J. Krynski & correspondence, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- "The directions of United States foreign policy and how Polish Americans can influence it" - Memorandum by Magnus J. Krynski, [n.d] (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Memoranda regarding sanctions to: (First name?)Kojelas, Senator William Armstrong, John Lenczowski, Ed Allison, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- “The economy as a component of foreign policy: the need for a long-range trade build down with the Soviet Bloc” by Magnus J. Krynski, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Amnesty International- Duke University Chapter- Speech & correspondence, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- The Committee for Workers’ Defense (KOR) background, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Aid For Poland- Chapel Hill, North Carolina- Newsletters, events, correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Polish-American-Club, North Carolina [formerly Aid to Poland]- Newsletters, events, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- North Carolina Committee for Solidarity with Solidarity (NCCSS)- Correspondence, newspaper articles, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- NCCSS- Press and media, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- POMOST- Information, agenda, correspondence, newsletters, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- POMOST- Correspondence with Chris Rac, Dave Wilke, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- POMOST- Correspondence with Andrzej Jermakowski, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- POMOST- Correspondence with Dave Domzalski/Committee in Support of Solidarity (Cleveland), 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Correspondence- Congressman Clement Zablocki, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- American Polish Political Action Committee (AMPOLPAC)- Information, correspondence, political activity, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- AMPOLPAC- Hartman, McLeod & Associates correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- AMPOLPAC- Federal Election Commission correspondence, newsletters, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Correspondence- Jan Kanty Miska regarding slander, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Freedom Federation- Meeting minutes, agenda, information about, newsletters, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Freedom Federation, International Trade Committee- Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Freedom Federation- Policy Statement on Poland, [n.d] (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Heritage Foundation- Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Heritage Foundation- Newsletters, 1978-1984 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- "Our moral Heritage" by Friedrich August von Hayek (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Correspondence- International Society for Human Rights/Eileen Padukov, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Correspondence- Paula Dobriansky/National Security Council, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Reinhard Gnauck, International Gesellschaft fur Menschenrechte (IGFM)- Correspondence, newsletter, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Correspondence- IGFM/Andrzej Zieba, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Correspondence- Regan-Bush ‘84, North Carolina Ethnic Voters/Michael Sotirhos, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- US Trade with Soviet Bloc- Correspondence, clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Notes on banking, [n.d] (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Siberian Pipeline- Correspondence, newspaper articles, U.S. Senate Transcript of Proceedings, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Voice of America- Correspondence, interviews, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Economic sanctions against Poland- Letters, Congressional Record, interview, clippings, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Lech Walesa on sanctions, December, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Sanctions- Polish American Congress letter to President R. Reagan, October 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- US Immigration Policy - clippings, correspondence, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Correspondence Magnus J. Krynski & North Carolina congressmen, newspaper articles, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- White House correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Committee in Support of Solidarity, New York- Correspondence, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Marek Lesniewski Laas- Support of Solidarity (Boston)- Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Committee for the Free World- Midge Decter- Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)